{ "cards":[
    {
        "front": "Cmd to display what version of git is installed",
        "back": "git --version"
    },
    {
        "front": "Cmd to display where git is installed.",
        "back": "which git"
    },
    {
        "front": "Steps to clone a github repository to desktop on Mac.",
        "back": "cd desktop\non Github.com select \"Clone or download\"\nSelect copy to clipboard https\non cmd line git clone https://to path"
    },
    {
        "front": "Cmd to navigate in child directory",
        "back": "cd NameOfDirectory"
    },
    {
        "front": "Cmd to list contents of directory.",
        "back": "ls"
    },
    {
        "front": "Cmd to show a list of most recent commits.",
        "back": "git log( uses 'less' which is a program to display text)\nescape by pressing 'q'"
    },
    {
        "front": "Create a file with VIM",
        "back": "vim filename"
    },
    {
        "front": "To insert text into a VIM editing session",
        "back": "Shift-Insert."
    },
    {
        "front": "Steps to fork and clone github repository.",
        "back": "select fork on github repository\nselect forked copy https://.."
    },
    {
        "front": "Pull request need to be ",
        "back": "forked first"
    },
    {
        "front": "Cmd to move up a directory",
        "back": "cd .."
    },
    {
        "front": "Cmd to remove a directory,  that isn't empty.",
        "back": "rm -rf  DirectoryToRemove"
    },
    {
        "front": "Confirm clone is a fork",
        "back": "git remote -v"
    },
    {
        "front": " Cmd to clear screen",
        "back": "clear"
    },
    {
        "front": "Create a repository",
        "back": "mkdir NewDirectory\ncd NewDirectory\ngit init"
    },
    {
        "front": "Cmd to list contents of directory including hidden files",
        "back": "ls -la"
    },
    {
        "front": "Find the status of new files , files to be commited to repository",
        "back": "git status"
    },
    {
        "front": "2 files that shoud be added to new respositories.",
        "back": "readme and license"
    },
    {
        "front": "Web site to find license information",
        "back": "choosealicense.com"
    },
    {
        "front": "Git configuration file",
        "back": "git config --list"
    },
    {
        "front": "Git adding a file to be commit",
        "back": "git add <file>"
    },
    {
        "front": "Git command to add all files.",
        "back": "git add ."
    },
    {
        "front": "VIM editor to save and escape",
        "back": "escape key  \"wq"
    },
    {
        "front": "Commiting files after git add",
        "back": "git commit\nopens defaut editor, save and commit"
    },
    {
        "front": "Git command to commit with a message.",
        "back": "git commit -m \"message here\""
    },
    {
        "front": "Git command to list commits.",
        "back": "git log "
    },
    {
        "front": "Git configuration options",
        "back": "git config --list"
    },
    {
        "back": "git config user.name \"YourUserName\""
    },
    {
        "front": "Git configurations local or global",
        "back": "git config --local or --global --list"
    },
    {
        "front": "Git readme files",
        "back": "README.md"
    },
    {
        "front": "CMD to print file to screen",
        "back": "cat <path/your_file>"
    },
    {
        "front": "Hidden file that  shows this is a Github clone",
        "back": ".git "
    },
    {
        "front": "List all remotes associated with current repo",
        "back": "git remote -v"
    },
    {
        "front": "What is a branch?",
        "back": "A branch in Git is simply a lightweight movable pointer to one of these commits. The default branchname in Git is master. As you initially make commits, you're given a master branch that points to the last commit you made. Every time you commit, it moves forward automatically."
    },
    {
        "front": "How is a branch created?",
        "back": "A branch is created when you fork a repository."
    },
    {
        "front": "List branches and remote branches being tracked.",
        "back": "git  branch -vv"
    },
    {
        "front": "Shows all branches local and remote",
        "back": "git branch -vv -all"
    },
    {
        "front": "Shows all commits.",
        "back": "git log --oneline"
    },
    {
        "front": "To add a local to a repository",
        "back": "git remote add origin "
    },
    {
        "front": "Adding a new extra remote to repo(not origin)",
        "back": "git remote add \"anyname\"  https://github.com/.....\ngit remote -v (will show the anyname and path of remote, Still need to fetch)\ngit fetch anyname"
    },
    {
        "back": "git log --oneline --decorate --all --graph"
    },
    {
        "front": "To push local changes to origin (could be asked for id/password) -pushing.",
        "back": "git push origin master"
    },
    {
        "front": "Adding a local to a repository -pushing.",
        "back": "git remote -vv\ngit remote add origin\ngit push --set-upstream origin master"
    },
    {
        "front": "Git command to see differences in files.",
        "back": "git diff"
    },
    {
        "front": "Git command to see diferences between commit",
        "back": "git log -p"
    },
    {
        "front": "Steps to add a directory because Git doesn't track directories only files",
        "back": "mkdir   name\ntouch name/.keep\ngit add .\ngit commit -m \"comment to add\"\ngit status\ngit log"
    }
]
}
